A Finding Aid to the Anna Coleman Ladd Papers, 1881-1950, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Scrapbooks, 1900-1940; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 0.3 Linear feet Box 3
  - Scrapbook 2, 1913-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook 2, 1913-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbook 2, 1913-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Scrapbook 2, 1913-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbook 2, 1913-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Scrapbook 2, 1913-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Scrapbook 3, 1923-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Scrapbook 3, 1923-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Scrapbook 3, 1923-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Scrapbook 3, 1923-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Scrapbook 3, 1923-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Scrapbook 3, 1923-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Scrapbook 3, 1923-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Printed Material, 1889-1942; Series 9; Archival Resource Key; 0.5 Linear feet Box 3, 6, OV 7
  Printed material includes clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs, programs, prospectuses, posters, brochures, autographed menus, booklets, and books. The programs are from Salisbury Cathedral, the Park Theatre, and Vassar College. The posters primarily reflect World War I topics including warnings against gas bombs. Brochures are primarily for lectures by Ladd. The menu dated 1921 is autographed by Cass Gilbert and Alfred Harding, Bishop of Washington. The books Meditations in Verse and Sundial Mottoes are autographed by the authors. Miscellaneous printed material includes engravings of anatomical diagrams.
  This series has been partially scanned. Only relevant pages of exhibition announcements with multiple artists and the covers, title pages, and relevant pages of published books have been scanned.
  - Clippings, circa 1910-1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Clippings, 1906; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Clippings, 1912; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Clippings, 1913; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Clippings, 1914; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Clippings, 1915; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Clippings, 1917; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Clippings, 1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Clippings, 1919; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Clippings, 1920-1921; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Clippings, 1923-1924; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Clippings, 1926-1928; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Clippings, 1930-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, circa 1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1916-1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1921-1925; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1930-1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Programs, 1905-1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Prospectuses, 1914-1916; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Posters, 1902-1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 40)
    Oversized material housed in Box 6, OV 7
  - Brochures, 1928; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Autographed Menus, 1921; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - "Contemporary American Sculptors,", circa 1914; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - "Le Procès de Jeanne d'Arc", as Presented by Madame Sarah Bernhardt, circa 1916; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - "A Vindication of President H. O. Ladd,", 1889; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - "Monographien zur Weltgeschichte,", 1898; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - "Hedwige D'Anjou," by M. Stanislas Smolka, 1907; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - "Mura Urbane,", 1911; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - "National Sculpture Society Constitution, Officers and Members," (1914-1915);"National Sculpture Society Constitution, Officers and Members," (1924-1925), 1914-1925; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - "Sculpture and Mural Paintings of the Panama-Pacific International Exposition,", 1915; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - "Official Miniature View Book of the Panama-Pacific International Exposition; Panama-Pacific International Exposition Report of the Department of Fine Arts", 1915; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - "Tre Figure Scomparse,", 1915; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - "Le Livre Rouge des Atrocités Allemandes,", 1916; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - "The Captivity of the Italians in Austria,", 1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - "La Petite Illustration Théatrale,", 1919; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - "The Work of Anna Coleman Ladd,", 1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - "Year Book of Poems,", 1925; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - "Gli Amori di Greta Garbo,", 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - "Third Reunion Bulletin of the Class of 1927,", 1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 59)
    (Vassar College)
  - "Le Manuscript Autographe,", 1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Epigrammes by Paul Verlaine, 1894; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Meditations in Verse by Jessie Eldridge Southwick, 1913; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - A Child Went Forth by Yoï Pawlowska, 1914; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Sundial Mottoes by Margaret L. Corlies, 1924; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Reproductions of Works of Art, 1913-1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Awards, circa 1890; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Newsletters, 1914-1915; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Oversized Printed Material, 1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 6)
    Oversized material scanned with Box 3, F29, 40, 65
  - Oversized World War I Posters, 1918; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 7)
    Oversized material scanned with Box 3, F40
- Photographs, 1881-1932; Series 10; Archival Resource Key; 0.8 Linear feet Box 4-6, MGP 1
  Photographs are of Anna Coleman Ladd, her family, friends, colleagues, her summer studio at Beverly Farms, Manchester, Massachusetts, her art work, and the art work of others. There is an autographed photo of Italian poet Giosuè Carducci, who won the Nobel Prize for Literature in 1906. Photographs of art work include an image of Ladd's work autographed by Bela Lyon Pratt. There is also a photograph of sculptor John Ettl in his studio. Additional photographs are found in Scrapbooks and Ladd's file on her portrait masks.
  This series has been partially scanned. Negatives have not been scanned.
  Existence and Location of Copies
  Glass plate negatives have been scanned.
  - Anna Coleman Ladd as a Child, 1881-circa 1890; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Anna Coleman Ladd as a Young Woman, 1900-circa 1906; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Anna Coleman Ladd with Artwork, circa 1909-circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Anna Coleman Ladd in Uniform and Snapshots, circa 1914-circa 1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Anna Coleman Ladd with Friends, circa 1900-circa 1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Dr. Maynard Ladd, circa 1900-1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Wedding, 1905; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Ladd Family, 1897-1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Friends and Colleagues, 1900-1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Friends and Colleagues, 1900-1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Friends and Colleagues, 1900-1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Friends and Colleagues, 1900-1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Houses, circa 1905; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - "Arden" Summer Studio, circa 1910; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Artist's Model, circa 1910; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Portrait Busts of Females, circa 1920s-circa 1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Portrait Busts of Males, circa 1920s-circa 1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Sculpture of Female Figures, circa 1920s-circa 1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Sculpture of Female Figures, circa 1920s-circa 1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Sculpture of Female Figures, circa 1920s-circa 1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Sculpture of Male Figures, circa 1920s-circa 1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Sculpture of Religious Figures, circa 1920s-1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Sculpture of Religious Figures, circa 1920s-1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Sculpture of Religious Figures, circa 1920s-1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Sculpture of Angels, circa 1920s-1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Sculpture of Soldiers and Warriors, circa 1920s-1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Sculpture of Putti and Nymphs, circa 1920s-1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Sculpture of Miscellaneous Figure Groups, circa 1920s-1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Sculpture for a Sundial and Birdbaths, circa 1920s-1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Fountain Sculpture, "Youth with the Blue Bird,", circa 1920s-1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Fountain Sculpture, "Triton Babies,", circa 1920s-1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Fountain Sculpture, "Ocean and Sail,", circa 1920s-1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Fountain Sculpture, "Wind and Spray,", circa 1920s-1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Fountain Sculpture, Unidentified, circa 1920s-1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Relief Sculpture, circa 1920s-1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Relief Sculpture, circa 1920s-1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Photographs of Miscellaneous Sculpture, circa 1920s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Art Work by Others, 1909-circa 1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Exhibition Installations, circa 1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Buildings, circa 1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Glass Plate Negatives, circa 1910; Archival Resource Key; 3 Glass negatives (Box MGP 1)
  - Oversized Photographs, circa 1900-circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 6)
    Oversized material scanned with Box 4, F6, 20, 21 and Box 5, F7